<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>dada-blog</title><link>http://davidovitch.github.com/dada-blog/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://davidovitch.github.com/dada-blog/feeds/all.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2012 21:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><item><title>About</title><link>http://davidovitch.github.com/dada-blog/about.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Why do blogs have pages about their authors? Why do I feel it is necessary to write something about myself here? The way I see it there are at least a couple of reasons for doing so. However, I will only elaborate upon a single one: the reason to put the blog into perspective. The title could have been "a full disclosure" for that matter. With an ever increasing influence of the social web 2.0 twitterish blogoshere, it is important, IMHO, that we know why certain people are saying what they are saying. As a reader it matters to me, I want to know if the writer of an article has a double agenda. If the arms lobby puts forward a spokesman stating that more arms will be beneficial for society, I know there is certain context that, partly, places such wild claims into perspective. Even though this blog, like many others, will have close to zero impact on the grand scheme of things I believe it matters. It is only fair and decent that we know who wrote something for what reason. All in the name of transparency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here goes, some dry facts about me, myself and I:
&lt;em&gt; born and raised in the region of Antwerp, Belgium (that's in Europe)
&lt;/em&gt; a Steinerschool (aka Waldorf school, &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steiner_school"&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;) adept, from kindergarten until the end of high school (3-18 years)
&lt;em&gt; studied &lt;a href="http://www.lr.tudelft.nl/en/"&gt;aerospace engineering&lt;/a&gt; at the TU Delft
&lt;/em&gt; masters degree in wind turbine engineering &lt;a href="http://www.duwind.tudelft.nl/"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;em&gt; during my studies it became clear to me that sustainability (being green, respect nature and human society, etc) is not only of paramount importance, but it is also a seriously interesting field in engineering
&lt;/em&gt; started a PhD at DTU Wind Energy in Denmark and that should be finished soon
* I actively support the Green political party in Flanders (their website: &lt;a href="http://www.groen.be"&gt;www.groen.be&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So any ramblings on find here can be expected to be of a left, greenish stamp.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">David Verelst</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2012 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:davidovitch.github.com/dada-blog,2012-01-08:about.html</guid><category>about</category></item><item><title>Initiate Blog</title><link>http://davidovitch.github.com/dada-blog/initiate-blog.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This is the content of my super blog post.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">David Verelst</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2010 10:20:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:davidovitch.github.com/dada-blog,2010-12-03:initiate-blog.html</guid><category>thats</category><category>awesome</category></item></channel></rss>