<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>dada-blog</title><link>/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://davidovitch.github.com/dada-blog/feeds/all.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 18:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><item><title>Over democratie, radicalisering en een perspectief daarop</title><link>/democratie-radicalisering-perspectief.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In de nasleep van de Charlie Hebdo aanslagen, en de geneutraliseerde terreurcel
in Vervier, vond ik het toepasselijk enkele observaties via een publiek kanaal
te delen. Daarbovenop, een kanaal dat niet ontsiert wordt door advertenties, of
dat tot doel heeft uw doen en laten te volgen voor haar eigen gewin (een licht
sarcastische knipoog naar Facebook en konsoorten).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Democratie&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://jmeblommaert.wordpress.com/"&gt;Jan Blommaert&lt;/a&gt; maakt enkele interessante
bedenkingen over hoe een krampachtig repressief antwoord op terreur dreigingen
de democratie fundamenteel uithollen. Het minste wat men daarover kan zeggen is
dat het ironisch is: het uithollen van democratisch verworven vrijheden om de
vrije democratie te beschermen. Hier is het artikel: 
&lt;a href="https://jmeblommaert.wordpress.com/2015/01/16/ik-ben-niet-bang-want-ik-ben-democraat/"&gt;Ik ben niet bang, want ik ben democraat&lt;/a&gt;.
Misschien klinkt het stuk hier en daar wat "radicaal", maar het bied voldoende
interessante stof om de discussie wat breder te kaderen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dit ironisch gegeven is ook De Morgen niet ontgaan met het volgend stuk:
&lt;a href="http://www.demorgen.be/technologie/europa-s-opmerkelijke-antwoord-op-de-aanslag-op-vrije-meningsuiting-meer-internetcensuur-a2179152/"&gt;Europa's opmerkelijke antwoord op de aanslag op vrije meningsuiting: meer internetcensuur&lt;/a&gt;.
Mijn eerste, eerder impulsieve reactie na het lezen van dit artikel:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;zucht, zucht, DIEPE zucht...anders doen we aan nog meer politieke
symptoombestrijding?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Radicalisering&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maar wat is dat eigenlijk, die radicalisering, waar we het allemaal zo gratuit 
over hebben? Patrick Loobuyck, moraalfilosoof aan de Universiteit Antwerpen en
de UGent, schreef er een interessant opiniestuk over in De Morgen:
&lt;a href="http://www.demorgen.be/opinie/radicalisme-is-pas-problematisch-als-men-met-geweld-zijn-overtuiging-ook-wil-opleggen-a2184737/"&gt;Radicalisme is pas problematisch als men met geweld zijn overtuiging ook wil opleggen&lt;/a&gt;.
Omdat ik vind dat de conclusie het heel helder samenvat, geef ik die hier nog eens:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Om kort te gaan, we kunnen radicale en fundamentalistische mensen vervelend
vinden en we hebben de vrijheid om ook als samenleving op hen in te praten - en
eenmaal er geweld in het geding is, moet politie en gerecht ingrijpen. Maar wat
kunnen we doen om te verhinderen dat radicale mensen de stap zetten naar geweld?
Dit is misschien wel de wezenlijkste vraag waar we nog het minst een duidelijk
antwoord op hebben.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blommaert sluit zijn stuk (dat ik onder hierboven onder Democratie eerder aanhaalde)
af met een anekdote van Dyab Abou Jahjah (niet mijn
grootste vriend maar de man heeft hier wel een punt ben ik bang): vanwege zijn
raciale uiterlijk werd hij, aan zijn eigen voordeur, door de politie onder schot
gehouden. Het incident haalde De Standaard
(&lt;a href="http://www.standaard.be/cnt/dmf20150116_01477301"&gt;Agenten viseerden me om mijn afkomst&lt;/a&gt;),
en staat meer uitvoerig beschreven op Facebook
(&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/dyab.aboujahjah.5?fref=ts]"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;).
Dit is nu reeds de realiteit in België, en ik denk dat Homans de bal flagrant 
misslaat in 
&lt;a href="http://www.demorgen.be/binnenland/homans-n-va-radicalisering-staat-los-van-discriminatie-a2185421/"&gt;Homans (N-VA): "Radicalisering staat los van discriminatie"&lt;/a&gt;.
Hoe kan dit soort racisme, stigmatisering, en een overijverige politie (laten
we ons vriendelijk uitdrukken) niet leiden tot frustratie, radicalisatie en 
een gewelddadige tegenreactie van de betrokkene?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;lectrr maakte er een leuke kartoon van op Twitter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en-gb"&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/cartoon?src=hash"&gt;#cartoon&lt;/a&gt;: 
&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/aboujahjah?src=hash"&gt;#aboujahjah&lt;/a&gt;
 tegengehouden door de politie &lt;a href="http://t.co/BvYS1U3GEX"&gt;pic.twitter.com/BvYS1U3GEX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &amp;mdash; lectrr (@lectrr) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/lectrr/status/556368017668710400"&gt;January 17, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Perspectief&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hoe zit dat eigenlijk met die families van die Syriëstrijders? Zijn dat eigenlijk
wel mensen? En uit wat voor een omgeving komen die, in België geboren en getogen
radicalen? Journaliste Saskia Vannieuwenhove hield hierover een interessante en
aangrijpende speech in Gent, naar aanleiding van de Charlie Hebdo aanslagen.
Nalezen kan &lt;a href="https://svannieuwenhove.wordpress.com/2015/01/11/charlie/"&gt;hier&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enkele quotes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kinderen van negen, tien, elf jaar die niet begrijpen waarom hun oom of vader
of broer is vertrokken. Gaan we tegen deze kinderen blijven zeggen “ge moet maar
uw verantwoordelijkheid nemen?” en al die groots klinkende repressiemiddelen
inzetten of gaan wij, allemaal samen, onze verantwoordelijkheid nemen en ook
deze kinderen omarmen, naar hun vragen luisteren en zorgen dat ze niet in die
risicocirkel blijven zitten van radicalisering?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;De afschuwelijke feiten die deze week in Parijs gebeurd zijn zijn geen louter
verhaal van wij-zij. Het is geen verhaal van de grote boze wereld versus het
westen. Het is geen verhaal van de islam. Het is een verhaal waar we op een
afschuwelijke manier hebben gezien wat ontworteling en uitsluiting en
‘van ons erf’ met mensen kan doen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">David Verelst</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 18:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:,2015-01-17:democratie-radicalisering-perspectief.html</guid><category>wind energy</category></item><item><title>Open tools for transparent participative and democratic decision making</title><link>/open-tools-for-participative-democracy.html</link><description>&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are ample problems in modern society, and I believe the democratic
process is an important pillar that needs additional love. The traditional top down decision making 
process is under pressure since it seems to favour well organized and wealthy 
groups who do not necessarily have any democratic backing. Some would argue that
influential
&lt;a href="http://corporateeurope.org/blog/lobby-power-surfaces-eu-election-campaign-theme"&gt;lobby&lt;/a&gt; 
groups in Brussels close to the European Commission are a good example of this.
When discussing politics and power in general we should at all times remember
that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Power tends to corrupt, and absolute power corrupts absolutely. 
Great men are almost always bad men. 
~ Sir John Dalberg-Acton, 8th Bt
(&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Power_corrupts"&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://www.phrases.org.uk/meanings/absolute-power-corrupts-absolutely.html"&gt;phrases.org&lt;/a&gt;
)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a practical perspective it seems surely more manageable to discuss top
level politics with a limited set of partners that represent industries, 
institutes, unions, people and alike. But then the internet happened which
could help scale the problem of democratic participation to a much larger group
of people. There are two steps in this process. The first would be to present
all working documents, opinions and consultations used in the decision making
process to the public (democratic transparency). Second step is to let the 
public actively engage with this process (in its extreme form this is a
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Direct_democracy"&gt;direct democracy&lt;/a&gt; or
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/E-democracy"&gt;e-democracy&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post will briefly cover some projects that are working on building
open source software tools to increase the number of people involved in the
democratic decision making process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;On-line collaborative decision making&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People unwilling to govern themselves will be ruled by those deemed unfit to govern.
~ Plato, The Republic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With &lt;a href="http://davidjarvis.ca/world-politics/"&gt;world politics&lt;/a&gt;,
David Jarvis outlines with a simple example how such a collaborative decision
making tool could look like. This open source concept is hosted on 
&lt;a href="https://bitbucket.org/djarvis/world-politics"&gt;Bitbucket&lt;/a&gt; and a worth while 
&lt;a href="https://bitbucket.org/djarvis/world-politics/wiki/Related%20Links"&gt;list of references&lt;/a&gt;
of similar systems is maintained as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the existing platforms in production use today present a very simple
interface for facilitating an on-line discussion around a proposal. For example,
with &lt;a href="https://demo.yrpri.org/"&gt;Your Priorities&lt;/a&gt; (developed on 
&lt;a href="https://github.com/rbjarnason/your-priorities"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;), you can cast votes
in favour and against, list pro's and con's, and engage in further discussion 
via a simple linear commenting thread. This approach seems suitable for simple
discussions and proposals involving a limited number of people, but I would argue
it will not scale properly to larger and more complex discussions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another example is &lt;a href="https://www.loomio.org/"&gt;Loomio&lt;/a&gt;. Although it is relatively
similar to Your Priorities, the interface, using nice looking graphs among others,
is more polished and thought through in my opinion.
You can see the tool in action on some live open projects 
&lt;a href="https://www.loomio.org/explore"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. An interesting feature that clearly
distinguishes Loomio from others is that you can cast 4 different kind of votes:
either in favour, abstain, against or veto.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I also find interesting about Loomio is how they are organized:
(and I quote from their web page):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loomio is built by a worker-owned cooperative. We’re a social enterprise
working to maximise positive social impact, not proﬁt &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After raising close to US$125,000 in a crowd-funding campaign, the open 
source development (taking place on &lt;a href="https://github.com/loomio/loomio"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;) 
is assured to continue for some time to come. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a final example I would like to mention &lt;a href="https://adhocracy.de/"&gt;Adhocracy&lt;/a&gt;,
yet another tool for democratic participation, developed by the German non-profit
&lt;a href="https://liqd.net/en/"&gt;LiquidDemocracy&lt;/a&gt; (code is on
&lt;a href="https://github.com/liqd/adhocracy/"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;). Although it doesn't look as slick 
as Loomio in my opinion, this framework has been under continuous development
over the last years and there is no sign of reduced
&lt;a href="https://github.com/liqd/adhocracy/graphs/contributors"&gt;activity&lt;/a&gt; either. 
Feature wise, the adhocracy platform is ahead of others by offering nested
discussion threads, more complex proposal description page including milestone
time line, map and member pages. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Challenges&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post very briefly looked at some open source tools that can be used for
on-line collaborative decision making. The reason why no propriety packages
are discussed here is because I think they are irrelevant in the context of 
transparency in governance: you can not trust a black box system
with the powers of crucial political decision making. However, developing and
maintaining such a system reliably exceeds the capabilities of a group of loosely
connected volunteers. Some sort of framework and funding has to be present.
In &lt;a href="http://spartakan.wordpress.com/2008/05/05/floss-projects-ande-pariticipation/"&gt;Does an opensource approach help e-democracy?&lt;/a&gt; 
this topic is explored in more detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is clear that a direct democracy with e-participation is not ready for today.
However, people are thinking about the problem and are making small steps
towards streamlined on-line decision making processes. Since there is a lot
to learn before getting there, every step counts!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When looking at projects such as Loomio and adhocracy, I believe that people
are moving towards more inclusive and participatory decision making processes.
Whether that is in small community teams, traditional companies or within
large national groups, it is a matter of time before they will become the norm.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">David Verelst</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 18:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>tag:,2014-06-01:open-tools-for-participative-democracy.html</guid><category>politics</category></item><item><title>Socio-economic-environmental-political science</title><link>/more-socio-economic-environmental-political-science.html</link><description>&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A naive and far from complete argument is presented here to suggest that political
decisions should be backed by more elaborate, open, and transparent studies
that guide policy makers today. This specific art form is defined here as
socio-economic-environmental-political science. At the end of the post the
respective Belgian context is briefly illustrated as an example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is socio-economic-environmental-political science?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am sure this definition is used literally in other places as well, but let's
define it clearly for this post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The act of transparently and openly estimating, monitoring and evaluating the
social, environmental and economical impact of legislation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would argue that this encompasses an in depth study of the interactions between
economics, sociology, the environment and politics. Typical questions I would
like to see being addressed could be&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the socio-economic return of extending a ring road in a densely
populated urban area? What are the environmental and public health issues, and
how do they relate to any economic return? What is the required political 
capital considering a range of opinions of interested parties, and what type of
solution is supported by how many people?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what I would call an impossible question to answer with great detail.
However, this is in reality a very typical problem encountered by politicians.
There is no way even a fraction of the solution space can be explored since so
many people's opinions are involved. Also, modelling the impact of certain
measures can not be done accurately within a short time frame. Yet during such
a decision making process many studies will be ordered and paid for. The results
of different studies will usually vary significantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not saying that these kinds of problems are not being investigated by
politicians. The point I try to make is that currently the performed
studies are islands, and their methodologies and data sets are not always 
clearly shared and motivated. The term reproducibility is nowhere to be found. A profound 
debate on assumptions, boundary conditions, data sets, and governing equations 
only takes place behind closed doors of the paid consultants executing the study.
Yet these decisions are important and shape the outcome of the study significantly. 
If a decision process is supposed to be democratic (which I clearly
think it should), then the studies supporting this process should be as open and
transparent as possible. Additionally, this could encourage democratic participation
from many different actors and organisations who have an interest in either the
process in itself or the outcome. For instance, 
mobility experts and engineers can review methodologies used assessing mobility
impacts, while economics can argue about the corresponding economic impact,
and environmental scientists contribute correspondingly. This widens the in origin
political debate significantly to other layers of society and that is a good thing.
In openly and transparently doing so, a broadly carried consensus is more likely to be found.
Additionally, it is often cheap to denounce studies ordered and paid by certain
political families or interest groups due to the assumed bias. If
studies carry a more neutral weight, such a political move might be expensive
in terms of public support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Politics needs its own Github: an open collaborative space where studies,
data, results, analysis can be shared, and discussed. How decisions are formed
should be tracked, pros and cons need to be clear at all times, and who's in
favour and against can be on display. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, creating such an environment is a huge challenge. 
Although far from trivial, the technical aspects are not the real problem as
the social internet industry (Github, Facebook, Twitter, Skype, ...)
demonstrates every day. Heck, people are already building an open source
infrastructure as we speak that could support such work flows, see for instance:
&lt;a href="https://liqd.net/en/"&gt;adhocracy&lt;/a&gt; (code is on &lt;a href="https://github.com/liqd/adhocracy/"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;)
and &lt;a href="https://www.loomio.org/"&gt;loomio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most difficult problem to tackle is to convince policy makers
that absolute transparency in the decision making process
(including the studies on which it bases itself) is the only way forward
to lift the democratic process to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Very short primer on Belgian politics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Belgian politics are a mess. I would assume politics are messy by definition,
but I am more familiar with the Belgian political scene than any other. 
Growing up as a native in a country usually has that effect. What particularly
makes Belgium such a mess is that we have close to 11 million inhabitants spread
over 3 semi independent small regions governed by no less than
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_governments_in_Belgium"&gt;six governments and parliaments&lt;/a&gt;.
However, the technicalities of the Belgian political scene and structure are not
the focus of this post. If you want to learn more about Belgium's political
structure, you can start browsing Wikipedia &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Belgium"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Politics_of_Belgium"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and 
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Political_parties_in_Belgium"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Independent review of promises made during election time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now to the Belgian context. When political parties layout their
campaigns and mark their priorities for the upcoming legislation, the
implications of proposed legislative measures
on the budget and society are at best guestimates. These guestimates are usually
created by in-house study groups employed by the respective political parties. 
Often these people have political ambitions as well, and it implies that the
presented studies are likely to be biased. For example, party A will present their studies
in support of the presented action plan. Parties C to Z will show exactly the
same positive results for wildly varying policies. In politics the solution
space for societal problems approaches infinity, and in the end it all boils
down to making choices and compromises, marking priorities and making decisions.
The downsides of these promised legislative choices are hardly emphasized
during campaigning, if at all. No transparent fact checking on the proposals is
performed, and used calculation methods and data sets are not shared openly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In The Netherlands the "Central Planning Bureau" 
(&lt;a href="http://www.cpb.nl/onderwerp/verkiezingen"&gt;CPB&lt;/a&gt;) acts as a third party
arbiter during election times verifying the economic context of the political claims.
In Belgium there is no such thing, there is no organised fact checking on what
political parties promise while seducing voters before the elections.
Applying a solid open and transparent socio-economic-environmental-political
science framework would in my opinion help the quality of the public debate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the upcoming 2014 &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elections_in_Belgium"&gt;elections&lt;/a&gt;
in Belgium, two parties have raised exactly these concerns.
You can read their brief statements as reported by Flemish newspaper The Standaard
&lt;a href="http://www.standaard.be/cnt/dmf20140129_044"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href="http://www.standaard.be/cnt/dmf20140129_00954330"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Not all is lost, and
at least some politicians agree at least partly with some of the statements 
placed here.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">David Verelst</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2014 18:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:,2014-03-16:more-socio-economic-environmental-political-science.html</guid><category>politics</category></item><item><title>Publications</title><link>/Publications.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Publication list&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">David Verelst</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:,2014-01-31:Publications.html</guid><category>Publications</category></item><item><title>About</title><link>/about.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Why do blogs have pages about their authors? Why do I feel it is necessary
to write something about myself here? The way I see it there are at least
a couple of reasons for doing so. However, I will only elaborate upon a
single one: the reason to put the blog into perspective. The title could
have been "a full disclosure" for that matter. With an ever increasing
influence of the social web 2.0 twitterish blogosphere, it is important,
IMHO, that we know why certain people are saying what they are saying. As
a reader it matters to me, I want to know if the writer of an article has a
double agenda. Even though this blog, like many others, will have close to
zero impact on the grand scheme of things I believe it matters. It is only
fair and decent that we know who wrote something for what reason. All in
the name of transparency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here goes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;born and raised in the region of Antwerp, Belgium (that's in Europe)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a Steinerschool adept (aka Waldorf school,
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steiner_school"&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;), from
kindergarten until the end of high school (3-18 years)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;professionally active in wind energy research: studied &lt;a href="http://www.lr.tudelft.nl/en/"&gt;aerospace
engineering&lt;/a&gt; at the TU Delft, did a PhD
at &lt;a href="http://www.vindenergi.dtu.dk/English.aspx"&gt;DTU Wind Energy&lt;/a&gt; in Denmark,
and decided to continue working there as a
&lt;a href="http://www.dtu.dk/Service/Telefonbog/Person?id=59332"&gt;post-doc&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;during my studies it became clear to me that sustainability (being green,
respect nature and human society, etc) is not only of paramount importance,
but it is also a seriously interesting field in engineering&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;seriously enthusiastic about the open source software and the corresponding
movement; needless to say, I am a Linux user (Arch Linux to be precise)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;actively support the &lt;a href="http://www.groen.be"&gt;Green political party&lt;/a&gt;
in Flanders&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;injustice, extreme greed, and inefficient engineering processes are my
pet peeves&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;art is important&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So any ramblings you will find here can be expected to be of a greenish
inspired kitchen, are often marinated with open source dogma's, and are
usually cooked on the left spectrum of the stove.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, please not that anything published in this blog solely represent my
personal opinion. They are not necessary endorsed by my current employer or any
other entity mentioned by name. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">David Verelst</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2012 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:,2012-01-08:about.html</guid><category>about</category></item></channel></rss>